Resume

Daniel Herrera

Daniel Herrera

3478371763 | danielaraujoherrera27@gmail.com | Brooklyn, NY 11222

SUMMARY

I am a reliable manager who demonstrates a high level of ownership and initiative. I possess an exceptional work ethic and desire to go above and beyond to exceed company expectations. I am offering the ability to build productive working relationships. I am successful in fast-paced environments and with deadlines to manage objectives and team development. I have a history of thriving in team-oriented environments. I am a motivational leader and organizational problem solver with advanced supervisory, teamwork and customer service skills. I have experience taking on roles and making positive changes quickly to drive company success. I am focused on the use of training, monitoring and morale-building techniques to maximize employee engagement and performance

*I am bilingual (English/Spanish) and am very interested in prospering in the path of business and finance

Skills

- Inventory Management
- Credit Card Transactions
- Workstation Maintenance
- Espresso Machine Operation
- Safe Food Handling Practices
- Relationship Building
- Coordinating Orders
- Food Storage Management
- Packaging and Labeling
- Verbal and Written Communication
- Machinery Troubleshooting and Maintenance
- Stocking Supplies and Retail Products
- Hospitality and Professionalism
- Product Advertising
- Payment Processing
- Customer Service
- Equipment and Store Cleaning Cash Handling

- Front of House Operations Equipment Checks and Assessments
- Process Control
- Organization and Prioritization
- Food Serving and Preparation
- Display Maintenance
- Speedy and Efficient
- Calm Under Pressure
- Solid Problem Solver
- Active Listener
- POS System Operation
- Food Preparation
- Cash Register Operation
- Team Leadership
- Team Player
- Marketing Strategies
- Account Management
- Client Needs Assessment spanish-english Translation
- Calm and Professional Under Pressure

Experience

Assistant General Manager, Quinoa Kitchen, September 2022-Current Brookly, NY

- Motivated and led team members to work together to achieve targets.
- Managed store cash intake with high accuracy and prepared daily bank deposits.
- Managed and mentored staff to carry out operational directives with high productivity and accuracy.
- Disciplined and maintained staff to deliver hospitable, professional service reflecting business initiatives.
- Applied knowledge of coverage needs and individual employee strengths to produce successful team schedules.
- Enhanced team engagement and performance with daily updates and informational meetings.
- Placed new inventory orders and oversaw correct restocking procedures to maintain operational output.
- *Identified customer needs and delivered relevant product solutions and promotions.*
- Helped team develop specialized projects, events and promotions.
- Supervised critical budget implementations, employee reviews, training and scheduling for projects.
- *Met business targets with streamlined operations strategies.*
- Delegated work to staff, setting priorities and goals.
- Completed thorough opening, closing and shift change functions to maintain operational standards each day.
- Used excellent verbal skills to engage customers in conversation and effectively determine needs and requirements.
- Monitored inventory levels and placed new orders for merchandise to keep supply wellstocked.
- Used strong issue resolution and communication skills to cultivate and strengthen lasting client relationships.
- Created effective business plans to focus strategic decisions on long-term objectives.
- Improved productivity initiatives, managing budgets and accounts, coordinating itinerary and scheduling appointments.

Kitchen Assistant, Quinoa Kitchen, November 2021-September 2022 Brookly, NY

- Maintained cleanliness and organization of kitchen stations and storage areas.
- Cleaned utensils, dishes and glasses for customer use.
- Supported chefs in managing food preparation to achieve precise plating and presentation.
- Followed recipes and customer requests to prepare meals.
- Stored perishable food items in freezer or refrigerator to protect from spoilage.
- Utilized kitchen equipment according to manufacturer's instructions and company safety protocols.
- Prepared dishes for catering events or during high-volume shifts.
- Acquired new skills to support team and further accommodate customer needs.
- Checked and recorded refrigerator and freezer temperatures to maintain food quality and freshness.
- Restocked pantry with nonperishable food items to prevent stock from running low.
- Observed food handling and sanitation procedures to safeguard against foodborne illnesses.
- Adjusted cooking methods and ingredients to accommodate dietary restrictions and food allergies.
- Maintained order and cleanliness of work areas to conform with health codes.
- Cleaned and sterilized dishes, countertops and utensils to prevent bacteria growth.
- Monitored inventory to keep adequate stock of food items and supplies.
- Partnered with chef to cook food and comply with food preservation guidelines.

Dishwasher, quinoa kitchen, November 2021-February 2022 Brooklyn, NY

- Scrubbed pots, pans and trays by hand or cleaned using industrial washing machine.
- Kept dishware, glasses and utensils ready for customer needs by quickly scraping, washing and restacking items.
- Sanitized counters and wiped down surfaces following food preparation to prevent cross-contamination from raw meats.
- Developed great team spirit with other personnel by pitching in and helping with task completion.
- Backed up kitchen team members during heavy work periods to maximize team coverage.
- Maintained assigned areas to keep organized and clean by mopping floor.
- Replaced clean utensils in storage bins for easy access.
- Studied methods of coworkers, successfully learning kitchen and food service skills.
- Transported clean dishes and supplies from kitchen to front of house staff for opening shift. Assisted chef with food measurements, preparation and storage when necessary.

Manager of Business Development and Sales, Cadutex, August 2018-April 2021 Merida, Venezuela

- Tracked monthly sales to generate reports for business development planning.
- Developed and implemented new sales strategies to update product lines.
- Oversaw management and implementation of new revenue strategies, sales initiatives and customer engagement tactics to increase market share.
- Established new accounts and serviced existing accounts maintaining professional relationships.
- Co-developed quota and compensation plan to motivate and reward sales staff.
- Reduced process gaps by hiring, supervising and coaching employees on sales strategies and protocols, optimizing performance, growth and profitability.
- Resolved customer complaints regarding sales and service.

Selling Agent, ICN98, February 2016-July 2017 Merida, Venezuela

- Communicated with clients to determine property needs and budget constraints.
- Advised clients on market conditions, pricing and legal requirements for property transactions.
- Identified potential buyers through cold calling.
- Prepared and delivered sales presentations.
- Promoted active listings through social media marketing, open houses and newsletters.
- Explained financial requirements and analytical data to potential buyers and sellers.
- Tracked weekly sales to develop senior leadership reports for corrective action planning.

Barista, Coffee Express, April 2010-June 2016 Merida, Venezuela

- Greeted and communicated with customers to take beverage orders and offer recommendations based on taste preferences.
- Prepared and served coffee, espresso drinks, blended coffees and teas.
- Managed morning rush of customers daily with efficient, levelheaded customer service.
- Maintained clean and organized workspace, enabling coworkers to locate resources and product.
- Memorized recipes for specialty coffee beverages and seasonal offerings.
- Followed health, safety and sanitation guidelines to pass state inspections.
- Memorized official and off-menu coffee and tea preparations.
- Restocked self-service area with sweeteners, stir sticks and coffee cup sleeves.
- Repaired minor issues with equipment and handled troubleshooting tasks to keep coffee machines operational.
- Prepared and served hot or cold beverages.

- Cleaned and sanitized service or seating areas, complying to health protocols and food safety standards.
- Input orders into point of sale system and handled customer payments.
- Described menu items to customers and suggested appealing products.
- Utilized coffee maker, espresso machine and French press to prepare coffee.
- Wrapped, labeled and dated food items for sale.
- Checked temperatures of freezers, refrigerators or heating equipment to verify proper functioning.
- Ordered and received supplies to restock beverage items.
- Sliced fruits, vegetables and meats for use in food service.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Económia, Facultad De Ciencias Economicas Y Sociales, Merida Venezuela

High School Diploma Colegio Arquidiosesano Madre Laura, Merida, Venezuela July 2013